<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gustavo Caso</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Gustavo Caso</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gustavocaso.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing a Ractor Base Job Scheduler</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/writing-a-ractor-base-job-scheduler/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/writing-a-ractor-base-job-scheduler/</guid><description>I was reading a fantastic article from my colleague Kir, and I could help myself to feel nerd snipped by:
For those curious to try Ractor, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest to try implementing other things that benefit from parallel execution, for instance a background job processor.</description></item><item><title>Building a CLI chat app with go and WebSockets</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/building-a-cli-chat-app-with-go-and-websockets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/building-a-cli-chat-app-with-go-and-websockets/</guid><description>With the current global situation and the need to stay home, I decided to finish writing this post that I started during the last Christmas holidays.
During Christmas, I wanted to learn more about the WebSockets protocol.</description></item><item><title>When open source has less benefits</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/when-open-source-has-less-benefits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/when-open-source-has-less-benefits/</guid><description>Here at Shopify, I work as a Production Engineer on the Jobs team. Our mission is to maintain and improve the background job infrastructure for Shopify Core, which happens to be one of the largest Ruby on Rails applications in the World.</description></item><item><title>Migrating millions of Redis keys without downtime</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/migrating-millions-of-redis-keys-without-downtime/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/migrating-millions-of-redis-keys-without-downtime/</guid><description>Last year in September I joined the Job Patterns team at Shopify.
The mission of the team is to provide a stable platform so that developers can write their background jobs to power one of the biggest e-commerce platforms in the world.</description></item><item><title>Summer Resolutions 2018</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/summer-resolutions_/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/summer-resolutions_/</guid><description>It has been a while since I blog 😥
A lot has happened in the last six months.
I started working for an English company based in London as a remote developer; I always wanted to work with a complete distributed team.</description></item><item><title>Grpc Tutorial with ruby</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/grpc-tutorial-with-ruby/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/grpc-tutorial-with-ruby/</guid><description>So the other day I found an exciting project Anycable that allow using custom WebSocket server within your ruby application. I immediately got hooked up, and I started reading about it, and the first thing that I never heard of it was Grpc.</description></item><item><title>Functional programming aspects of the Ruby language</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/functional-programming-aspects-of-the-ruby-language/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/functional-programming-aspects-of-the-ruby-language/</guid><description>Revised by Andy Holland
Lately, there has been a significant change in the industry towards functional programming, new languages have appeared: Elixir, Scala, Elm.
With all this new hype I decided to give a try to some of them, and I have to say that they are really cool, but wether I like it at work I mostly use ruby.</description></item><item><title>Dry-web-roda for Rails Developers Part II (Persistence)</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/dry-web-roda-for-rails-developers-part_ii-persistence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/dry-web-roda-for-rails-developers-part_ii-persistence/</guid><description>Following with my previous post, Dry-web-roda part 1, I have decided to create my own small website to keep track of all the things I learn throughout the day.
Yes, I know, another Today I Learned Website 😓 - til_web, but this time I started with the persistence layer and I wanted to share my experience with you.</description></item><item><title>Dry-web-roda for Rails Developers Part I</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/dry-web-roda-for-rails-developers_part_i/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/dry-web-roda-for-rails-developers_part_i/</guid><description>Revised by Piotr Solnica and Andy Holland
Lately, I have been playing around and contributing to the great ecosystem of dry-rb, first of all, I have to say the community is absolutely fantastic, super supportive and eager to welcome many new contributors.</description></item><item><title>My Setup with rvm, gemsets and bundler</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/my-setup-with-rvm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/my-setup-with-rvm/</guid><description>I took me some time, to figure out how to correctly setup every project I worked on, not that I work in tons of projects, but now that I have a better understanding of how to setup, it makes more sense to me, at least.</description></item><item><title>React back to basics</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/react-back-to-basics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/react-back-to-basics/</guid><description>This is not going to be another post describing React and what is good or what is bad about it, I&amp;rsquo;m just learning it, and part of the learning process I decided that I will write a blog post for helping me maintain this new concepts.</description></item><item><title>Back from summer resolution</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/back-from-summer-resolution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/back-from-summer-resolution/</guid><description>After a long vacation, I came with a lot of energy and new goals for the new year.
So I decided that I&amp;rsquo;m going to start making things right, been a developer is not always easy, you have to continuosly update your knowledge and keep practicing even outside office hours.</description></item><item><title>Testing Comamnd-Line Applications with Aruba</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/testing-command-line-applications-with-aruba/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/testing-command-line-applications-with-aruba/</guid><description>In the last couple of weeks I have been working, with a little project of my own. I always love Command Line Tools, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what they have but using them make feel more like a Hackers or someone that actually know what he is doing.</description></item><item><title>Testing your rake tasks</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/testing-your-rake-tasks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/testing-your-rake-tasks/</guid><description>This is the second part of my previous post Improving our rake tasks.
In this one we will discuss a way for testing our rake task, the example will be very straight forward.</description></item><item><title>Improving our rake tasks</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/improving-our-rake-tasks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/improving-our-rake-tasks/</guid><description>Lately I have been writting some rake tasks, for downloading backups, for accesing API&amp;rsquo;s, or for automating teadious and repetitive work. Rake task are great, but dangerous at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Working your way up with promises</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/working-your-way-up-with-promises/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/working-your-way-up-with-promises/</guid><description>#####Promises, what ??
I consider myself a ruby developer, not one with long time professional experience, but one with a great attitude and eager to learn new technologies.
Lately I have been working more with JavaScript at the beginning I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really enthusiastic about the idea of working with JavaScript but the project itself really surprise me.</description></item><item><title>Using Rails Resolver Api</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/using-rails-resolver-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/using-rails-resolver-api/</guid><description>#####Implement Rails Variants in Rails 3.1
Yesterday at work we decided that we need to improve our user experience in web mobile. So we decided that it was time to create a different view for each action.</description></item><item><title>Decorator Pattern</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/decorator-pattern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/decorator-pattern/</guid><description>Last night I was reading some blogs about ruby patterns, for me is sometimes difficult to understand the use of this kind of patterns, mostly because in my work we just throw thousand of lines of code, and deal with a lot of legacy code from other person who contribute to our projects.</description></item><item><title>Set up a simple deployment system</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/set-up-a-simple-deployment-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/set-up-a-simple-deployment-system/</guid><description>Before deploy in production is always recommended to test everything first, probably you have a Test suit for test your application, but you never know want is going to happen when you deploy all changes to production.</description></item><item><title>Self-referential Associations</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/self-referential-associations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/self-referential-associations/</guid><description>When I first heard about this concept I was a little bit confuse. I was reading Learn rails by Example by Michael Hart
By that time the concept was to much for me, so I did some research.</description></item><item><title>Enumerator</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/enumerator-lazy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/enumerator-lazy/</guid><description>Recently reading the some posts about ruby I found myself with this interesting method call lazy. This method will help us when looping over some objects: Array, Hashes, Files &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;. If you want to loop though an array that is huge, an we only want to select the first 20 element that evaluate our criteria, this is the kind of job for our lazy method.</description></item><item><title>Inverse_of ActiveRecord</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/inverse-of/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/inverse-of/</guid><description>While reading the documentation of ActiveRecord::Associations, there are many useful methods, that I didn´t know about it. But one came to me as quite useful, inverse_of. This method allow us to work with associations that haven`t been save yet, so it will work with the memory.</description></item><item><title>Exporting and Import Heroku DB</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/exporting-and-import-heroku-db/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/exporting-and-import-heroku-db/</guid><description>Recently I was playing around with my local database in my rails project, eventually I screw up, I had to delete all the data. I use rake db:resetand rake db:create but how I was going to get all the data again, manually ?</description></item><item><title>Delayed job and Send email with Attachements</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/delayed-job-and-send-email/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/delayed-job-and-send-email/</guid><description>Sending emails with rails and Heroku (Updated 2014-04-24)
Rails makes extremly easy to send emails, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to explain how to do it, there are pretty good tutorials around the internet, this one is really well explain: Action Mailer Basics.</description></item><item><title>Integrate Disqus with Octopress</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/integrate-disqus-with-octopress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/integrate-disqus-with-octopress/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m new to Octopress platform for Blogging, but so far I think is great and simple.
Creating my first post I felt so excited, as when you discover a new treasure or a secret path in your favorite game.</description></item><item><title>Rails and select</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/rails-and-select/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/rails-and-select/</guid><description>In a rails project I&amp;rsquo;m working on I was trying to select from the database some sales with some conditions.
To start the Sale model has multiples associations .
class Sale &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base belongs_to :voucher belongs_to :client has_many :line_items, dependent: :destroy has_many :bills end So the goal of this select was to obtain all the Sales where the LineItems has express_checkout set it to true.</description></item><item><title>Rails Postgresql Error ORDER clause</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/rails-postgresql-error-order/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/rails-postgresql-error-order/</guid><description>Postgresql ORDER clause or be used in a aggregate function
While working in a rails project recently, I step on an error that say: PG::Error: ERROR: column &amp;quot;number&amp;quot; must appear in the GROUP BY clause or be used in an aggregate function, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any idea how to solve it.</description></item><item><title>File rename in ruby</title><link>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/file-rename-in-ruby/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gustavocaso.dev/posts/file-rename-in-ruby/</guid><description>While doing some exercise of the book Learn to Program of Chris Pine, trying to rename some files as part of some exercise, that was renaming a bunch of picture from a folder, I noticed a strange functionality.</description></item></channel></rss>